Guide to the Kenneth J. Arrow Papers, 1921-2017 RL.00052
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Email Correspondence, 1999-2017 and undated
  - Email Correspondence, 2006; 3608 messages, 350 MB. (Digital-materials RL00052-SET-0001)
    Includes professional and personal correspondence, notable correspondents include Simon Levin, James Heckman, Tim Bresnahan, Ariel Rubinstein
  - Email Correspondence, 2007; 11478 messages, 722 MB. (Digital-materials RL00052-SET-0001)
    Includes professional and personal correspondence, notable correspondents include Myrna Wooders, Simon Levin, David Starrett, Paul Ehrlich, Tim Bresnahan, Thomas Sargent, James Heckman
  - Email Correspondence, 2008; 13135 messages, 974 MB. (Digital-materials RL00052-SET-0001)
    Includes professional and personal correspondence, notable correspondents include Partha Dasgupta, Nathan Rosenberg, Eric Maskin, Roger Myerson, Robert Aumann, Martin Shubik
  - Email Correspondence, 2009; 1368 messages, 7 MB. (Digital-materials RL00052-SET-0002)
    Includes porfessional and personal correspondence, notable correspondents include Michael Intriligator, Simon Levin, Roger Myerson, Partha Dasgupta, Tim Bresnahan, Robert Aumann
  - Email Correspondence, 2009; 868 messages, 54 MB. (Digital-materials RL00052-SET-0002)
    Includes professional and personal correspondence, notable correspondents include Partha Dasgupta, Amartya Sen, Michael Intriligator, and Herbert Scarf.
  - Email Correspondence, 2010; 1580 messages, 106 MB. (Digital-materials RL00052-SET-0002)
    Restricted until 2020. Contact Research Services to request access from Arrow's family.
    Includes professional and personal correspondence, notable correspondents include Partha Dasgupta and Michael Intriligator..
  - Email Correspondence, 2011; 3075 messages, 310 MB. (Digital-materials RL00052-SET-0002)
    Restricted until 2021. Contact Research Services to request access from Arrow's family.
    Includes professional and personal correspondence, notable correspondents include Simon Levin, Partha Dasgupta, Paul Ehrlich, and Nathan Rosenberg.
  - Email Correspondence, 2012; 3973 messages, 815 MB. (Digital-materials RL00052-SET-0002)
    Restricted until 2022. Contact Research Services to request access from Arrow's family.
    Includes professional and personal correspondence, notable correspondents include Simon Levin, Partha Dasgupta, Paul Ehrlich, James Heckman, Martin Shubik, Robert Aumann.
  - Email Correspondence, 2013; 3434 messages, 550 MB. (Digital-materials RL00052-SET-0002)
    Restricted until 2023. Contact Research Services to request access from Arrow's family.
    Includes professional and personal correspondence, notable correspondents include Larry Summers, Martin Shubik, Alvin Roth, Ross Starr.
  - Email Correspondence, 2014; 4270 messages, 710 MB. (Digital-materials RL00052-SET-0002)
    Restricted until 2024. Contact Research Services to request access from Arrow's family.
    Includes professional and personal correspondence, notable correspondents include Tim Bresnahan, Michael Woodford, Martin Shubik, and Robert Aumann.
  - Email Correspondence, 2015; 4578 messages, 760 MB. (Digital-materials RL00052-SET-0002)
    Restricted until 2025. Contact Research Services to request access from Arrow's family.
    Includes professional and personal correspondence, notable correspondents include Tim Bresnahan, Eric Maskin, Robert Aumann, and Martin Shubik.
  - Email Correspondence, 2016; 7037 messages, 1 GB. (Digital-materials RL00052-SET-0002)
    Includes professional and personal correspondence, notable correspondents include Paul Ehrlich, John Geanakoplos, and Eric Maskin.
  - Email Correspondence, 2017; 6373 messages, 480 MB. (Digital-materials RL00052-SET-0002)
    Restricted until 2027. Contact Research Services to request access from Arrow's family.
    Includes professional and personal correspondence.
  - Email Correspondence, undated, 37 messages, 317 KB. (Digital-materials RL00052-SET-0002)
    Unsorted e-mail messages, contains mostly advertisements
- Professional Service, 1970s-2015
  This series includes files on Arrow's various professional activities. These include: conference and workshop presentations; public lectures; files related to service with professional organizations and research institutes and organizations; files from advising on award committees and journal editorial boards; expert witness testimony; and files documenting Arrow's political activities.
  - Conferences, Consulting, and Organizations, 1970s-2015; 1
    Includes Arrow's conference and public lecture presentations and administrative work for various committees and institutions, as well as his work as a paid consultant on several projects. The latter includes three extended projects, one on economic growth and policy for the Canadian Institute for Advanced Research, one on climate change for the National Academy of Sciences and one on contingent valuation (the use of surveys to value public goods) for the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Association. The former includes work for the American Economic Association, International Economic Association, National Bureau of Economic Research, as well as for the City College of New York, the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development, RAND, Beijer, the National Science Foundation, the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, the Nobel nomination committee, and numerous other organizations.
    Electronic records in this sub-series have been migrated to a library server and digital use copies can only be accessed onsite in the Rubenstein Library Reading Room.
    - A., Misc., 1998-2008 (Box 19)
    - Abrams Lectures, 1984-1991; 7 folders (Box 19)
      Includes draft speeches
    - Abt Associates, 1979-1986; 2 folders (Box 47)
      Files related to serving on board of directors
    - Actuaries' Club, 1978 (Box 19)
    - AEA (American Economic Association): 1990, 1989-1990 (Box 19)
    - AEA, 2000-2014 (Box 19)
    - AEA: 2004 (Box 47)
      Files related to conference presentation
    - AEA: 2013, 2012-2013 (Box 19)
    - AEA: Anaheim 1993, 1992-1993 (Box 19)
    - AEA: ASSA 2009, 2008-2009 (Box 19)
    - AEA: Boston 1994 - Ely Lecture, 1993-1994 (Box 19)
    - AEA: Chinese-American Exchange, 1992-1993 (Box 47)
    - AEA: Committee on Political Discrimination, 1974-1979; 3 folders (Box 47)
      Files related to serving as chair of American Economic Association Committee on Political Discrimination in the economics profession
    - AEA: Committee on USSR Relations, 1991 (Box 47)
    - AEA: Dallas 1984, 1982-1985 (Box 19)
    - AEA: Economic Theory Session 1989 (Box 19)
    - AEA: Graduate Training, 1988-1991; 7 folders (Box 47)
      Files related to Committee on Graduate Education in Economics
    - AEA: Miscellaneous, 1992 (Box 47)
    - AEA: Social Science Research Council, China Exchange, 1980-1993 (Box 47)
    - AEA: South African Students, 1990-1993 (Box 47)
    - AEA: Washington 1995 (Box 19)
    - AFA Fellows, 2013 (Box 63)
    - Affaires Mondiale, 1994 (Box 19)
    - AFOSR Workshop, 2012-2013 (Box 19)
    - AIDS Conference-Kirman, 2003 (Box 19)
    - Aix-Marseilles Center, 1980-1993; 3 folders (Box 28)
      Files related to serving on scientific committee for the center, as well as receiving honorary degree
    - Alaska, 1988 (Box 47)
    - Alaska Evidence, 1982 (Box 47)
      Files for members of Alaska Permanent Fund Corporation Board of Trustees
    - All Souls College, 1996 (Box 19)
      Seminar on the "Economics of Information Diffusion"
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences: Western Center, 1991-1993 (Box 47)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1976-2013; 3 folders (Box 28)
      Files related to serving on membership committee
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences: Electorate, 1991 (Box 28)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences: IIASA, 1982-1994; 2 folders (Box 28)
      Files related to serving on advisory committee for International Institute for Applied Systems Analysis as part of AAAS
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences: Nominations, 1981-2005 (Box 47)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences: Wester Center, 1990-1992; 2 folders (Box 28)
      Files related to serving on Executive Council
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1983-1995; 2 folders (Box 47)
      Files related to serving as council chair and advisory committee
    - American Association of Science: Electorate Nominating Committee, 1994-1996 (Box 47)
    - American Association of University Professors, 1991 (Box 47)
    - American Council for an Energy Efficient Economy, 1982-1987 (Box 47)
    - American Economic Review, 1977 (Box 47)
    - American Federation of Scientists, 1997 (Box 47)
    - American Finance Association, 2003-2013 (Box 19)
    - American Foreign Policy, Inc., 1976-1977 (Box 47)
      Files related to serving on honorary board of directors
    - American Philosophical Society, 1987-2012; 2 folders (Box 19)
    - American Philosophical Society, 1974-1977 (Box 47)
      Files related to serving on membership nominations committee
    - American Prospect, The, 1988-1993 (Box 47)
      Files related to serving on editorial board
    - American Society for Technion, 1975 (Box 47)
    - American Statistical Association, 1974 (Box 47)
    - Americans for Peace Now, 1991 (Box 19)
    - AMFm (Affordable Medicines Facility - malaria): Renewal, 2012 (Box 19)
      Files related to serving on advisory group for Affordable Medicines Facility-malaria initiative within The Global Fund
    - AMFm: Review, 2012 (Box 19)
    - Amsterdam Royal, 1996-1997 (Box 19)
      Lecture on "Economy and Ecology" at Amsterdam Royal Palace Foundation
    - Annual Review, 2006-2015 (Box 47)
      Files related to serving as editor
    - APSA (American Political Science Association) Meeting, 1997 (Box 19)
    - Arab Health Water Association, 2007 (Box 19)
    - Arrow Lecture 2012 (Box 19)
    - Arrow Lecture 2014 (Box 19)
    - Arrow Lecture: Columbia Lecture, 2013 (Box 19)
    - Arrow Lectures, 1991-2011 (Box 19)
    - Arrow Lectures: Columbia, 2008-2009 (Box 19)
    - Arrow Prize (Berkeley), 2004-2005 (Box 47)
    - Arrow-Hurwicz Workshop, 1977 (Box 19)
      Talk on "Informational Issues in Decentralization"
    - Arthur Andersen, 1998 (Box 47)
      Files related to Centre for Stakeholder Research
    - Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation High Level Meeting, 2013 (Box 19)
    - Asko, Finland 2014 (Box 19)
    - ASSU (Associated Students of Stanford University) Conference, 1984 (Box 19)
    - Australia, 1998 (Box 19)
      Documents related to keynote address at Australian Conference of Economists
    - Baky, 2012 (Box 19)
      Documents related to conference hosted by Baky International Humanitarian Forum
    - Banca Nazionale Del Lavoro Quarterly Review, 1996 (Box 47)
    - Barcelona, 1999 (Box 19)
      Lecture on "Networks in Economic Questions"
    - Barcelona Graduate School, 2005-2015; 2 folders (Box 47)
    - Barcelona Lecture, 1990 (Box 19)
      Talk on "Excellence and Equity in Education"
    - Baruch Talk, 2014 (Box 19)
    - Basel Conference, 1987 (Box 19)
      Talk on "Survival and Growth in a Polycentric World Economy"
    - BBVA Fund, 2012-2013 (Box 47)
      Files related to serving on Fund's awards committee
    - Behavioral Foundations of Economic Theory Conference, 1984-1986 (Box 19)
      Talk on "Rationality of Self and Others in an Economic System"
    - Beijer, 1999-2006 (Box 19)
      Files related to Beijer Institute Fellowship and events
    - Beijer Asko, 2000-2012; 9 folders (Box 19)
      Files related to annual meeting at Beijer Institute
    - Beijer Excess Consumption Irreversibility, 2004-2005 (Box 19)
    - Beijer FEEM Knowledge Conference, 2000-2001 (Box 19)
    - Beijer Institute, 1993-2002 (Box 48)
    - Beijer Stanford, 2006 (Box 19)
    - Beijer: Environment and Development Economics, 2000-2011 (Box 48)
    - Beijer: Excess Consumption, 2001-2004; 3 folders (Box 48)
    - Beijer: Sandee, 2003 (Box 19)
    - Beijer: Venice, 1997 (Box 19)
    - Beijer: Yucatan, 2001 (Box 19)
    - Beijing 2009 Peking University (Box 19)
      Documents related to participation in Beijing Forum
    - Bellagio Conference, 1992 (Box 19)
    - Benefit-Cost Analysis, 2008-2009 (Box 19)
      Files related to Society for Benefit-Cost Analysis
    - Ben-Gurion University of the Negev, 1990-1998 (Box 48)
      Files related to serving on board of governors
    - Bergen, 2001 (Box 19)
      Documents related to 50th anniversary seminar at the Norwegian School of Economics and Business Administration
    - Berkeley Centennial, 2002 (Box 19)
      Presentation on "Equilibrium, Time, Uncertainty, and Knowledge" at Berkeley Centennial Celebration
    - Berkeley Mathematical Sciences Research Institute, 1981-1983 (Box 48)
      Files related to serving on program committee
    - Berlin WZB Lecture, 1994 (Box 19)
      Lecture on current developments in economics
    - Biblical Economics, 2000 (Box 19)
    - Bioeconomics, 1984-1985 (Box 48)
      Files related to Journal of Social and Biological Structures
    - Bioethics Center, 2001 (Box 19)
    - Bishops - Pastoral Letter on Catholic Social Teaching, 1984-1985 (Box 48)
    - Bounded Rationality, 1989 (Box 19)
      Presentation on bounded rationality given at National Science Foundation seminar
    - Brown U: von Neumann Lecture, 2010 (Box 20)
      Talk on "My Beliefs and Ours: Formation, Costs, Interactions, and Effects"
    - Brown University, 2014 (Box 20)
      Invitation to speak at Brown University
    - Bruno Memorial, 1997 (Box 20)
      Lecture given at memorial conference for Michael Bruno
    - Bundeskanzler Fellowship, 1992 (Box 48)
    - Caffe Lectures, 2000 (Box 48)
      Lecture on economic networks
    - Camp Lectures, 1978-1980; 2 folders (Box 20)
      Files related to lecture series on the "Possibility of Economic Policy", "The Economics of Detail", and "The Possibility of Socialism"
    - Canadian Institute for Advanced Research, 1994-2002; 2 folders (Box 20)
      Documents related to serving on advisory committee for Canadian Institute for Advanced Research
    - Canadian Institute for Advanced Research, 1989-1994; 3 folders (Box 48)
      Files related to serving on Economic Growth Advisory Committee
    - Carey Lecture, 1996 (Box 20)
      Lecture on conflict and resolution given at Colorado College
    - Catastrophic Risk, 1994 (Box 20)
      Catastrophic Risk Conference
    - Centennial Symposia, 1990 (Box 20)
      Files related to Stanford's Centennial Symposium
    - Center for European Studies, 1990-1991 (Box 48)
    - Center for Foundational Studies, 1987 (Box 48)
    - Center for Health Policy, 2002-2003 (Box 20)
    - Center for National Policy, 1981-1987 (Box 48)
      Files related to serving on National Advisory Board
    - Center for Poverty and Inequality, 2006-2007 (Box 20)
    - Center for Rationality and Interactive Decision Theory, 1991-2009 (Box 20)
      Files from serving on Academic Committee for center
    - Center for Risk Analysis, 1986-1987 (Box 48)
    - Center for Robust-Decision, 2009 (Box 20)
    - Center for Study in Israel, 1979 (Box 48)
    - Center on Ethics, 2005-2013; 2 folders (Box 20)
      Files related to Stanford Center on Ethics in Society
    - CEPR (Center for Economic and Policy Research): IEA Conference, 1986-1994; 5 folders (Box 20)
      Files for CEPR conference on Public Debt
    - CEPR: Search, 1989 (Box 48)
      Files related to search committee for director of CEPR
    - CEPREMAP (Centre pour la Recherche Economique et ses Applications), 1974-1975 (Box 48)
      Files related to Centre d'Études Prospectives d'Économie Mathématique Appliquées a la Planification
    - CERES, 1992 (Box 20)
      Files for CERES Conference on Global Food and Technology Issues
    - CERGE-EI (Center for Economic Research and Graduate Education - Economics Institute), 1996 (Box 20)
      Files related to lecture given at Charles University, Czech Republic
    - Charles River Associates, Inc., 1984 (Box 48)
    - China 2000 (Box 20)
      Presentation on economic growth in China for China 2000 Conference
    - China Center for Labor, 2008-2009 (Box 20)
      Files related to keynote speech at conference on Human Capital in China
    - China Trip Diary, 1979 (Box 20)
      Notes from work trip and meetings in China
    - Chinese Academy of Social Science, 1994 (Box 20)
    - Chinese Economists Society, 1988-2013 (Box 20)
      Files related to serving as advisory member for Chinese Economists Society
    - Chinese Finance Association, 1996 (Box 20)
    - Chinese Information Science, 1992 (Box 20)
    - Chocolate Group Talk, 2000 (Box 20)
      Transparencies for lecture given to "Chocolate Group"
    - Chung-Hua Lecture, 1982-1995 (Box 48)
    - CIH, 1993 (Box 20)
    - CISAC (Confederation Internationale des Societes d'Auteurs et Compositeurs), 2006-2016 (Box 20)
      Files from serving on Center for International Security and Cooperation advisory board
    - City College Minorities Center, 1989-1990 (Box 48)
      Files related to serving on advisory committee
    - City College of New York, 1973-1979; 2 folders (Box 48)
    - City College Scholarship Endowment, 1977 (Box 48)
    - Clarendon Lectures, 1987-1996 (Box 48)
    - Clean Air Statement Nobel, 1989 (Box 48)
      Files related to Nobel laureates endorsing tradeable permits to control acid rain
    - Clinch River, 1983 (Box 48)
      Files related to evaluating Clinch River Nuclear Reactor project
    - Clinton Campaign, 1992 (Box 48)
      Files related to commentary on Clinton's proposed economic policies
    - Coase Institute, 2000-2015; 3 folders (Box 20)
      Files from serving on board of Ronald Coase Institute
    - Collegium Budapest, 1993 (Box 20)
    - Collier Paper, 2008 (Box 20)
      Notes on paper presentation
    - Columbia: Capitalism and Society, 2011 (Box 20)
    - Committee for Economic Recovery, 1981 (Box 48)
      Files related to committee meeting
    - Complexity (journal), 1991 (Box 48)
    - Complexity Workshop, 1986 (Box 20)
    - Conferences, Consulting, and Organizations electronic records, 1993-2016; Approximately 850 files derived from 3 floppy disks and external drive; 192 MB. (Digital-materials RL00052-SET-0003)
      Includes files related to conferences and workshops
    - Conflict Resolution, 2001 (Box 20)
      Presentation on the economics of conflict resolution
    - Conservatoire National des Arts et Métiers, 1979 (Box 48)
      Files related to serving on scientific advisory board
    - Contingent Valuations and Environment, 1984 (Box 20)
      Presentation given at conference hosted by University of New Mexico
    - CORE (Center for Operations Research and Econometrics), 1973-1986; 2 folders (Box 48)
    - Cornell - Computer Economics, 2009 (Box 48)
      Report related to NSF-sponsored workshop
    - Cornell Talk, 2001 (Box 20)
      Presentation on "Making Provisions for the Future"
    - Cowles Symposium, 1983-1989; 3 folders (Box 20)
      Papers, notes, and files associated with the Cowles Foundation 50th anniversary conference and edited volume
    - CUHK (Chinese University of Hong Kong), 2008 (Box 20)
      Lecture on discounting at Chinese University of Hong Kong
    - Current Wisdom, 1988 (Box 48)
      Files related to declining invitation for involvement in Current Wisdom organization
    - Cyert: March, 2013 (Box 20)
    - Cyprus Visit, 2000 (Box 20)
      Presentation on "The Economic Way of Thinking" at University of Cyprus
    - Dartmouth Review, 1993 (Box 48)
      Correspondence related to serving on advisory board
    - Debreu Memorial, 2005-2006 (Box 21)
      Talk and notes from Debreu memorial conference
    - Decision and Discretion, 2001 (Box 21)
      Presentation at symposium organized by American Association for Artificial Intelligence
    - Decision Analysis Workshop, 2011 (Box 21)
    - Delhi School of Economics - Centre, 1992 (Box 48)
      Files related to proposed Centre for Development Economics
    - Democratic Socialists Organizing Committee, 1975-1978 (Box 48)
      Files related to statement urging research on alternatives to capitalism
    - Democratic Study Group, 1983 (Box 48)
      Files related to Walter Mondale's economic policies
    - Differential Information, Market Failure, and Public Policy, 1977-1980 (Box 21)
      Lecture given at University of California - Irvine
    - Disorder and Order, 1981 (Box 21)
      Lecture given at Stanford Symposium on Disorder and Order
    - DRASH, 1987 (Box 48)
    - E., Misc., 1982-2009 (Box 21)
    - Earth Day, 1990 (Box 48)
    - Earth Institute, 2008 (Box 21)
      Files from serving on board of Earth Institute
    - Eastern Europe Conference, 1989 (Box 21)
      Conference on Eastern European transition
    - East-West Center, 1974-1975 (Box 48)
    - EBRD (European Bank for Reconstruction and Development), 1990-1998; 3 folders (Box 49)
      Files related to serving on advisory board
    - EBRD: April 1993 Meeting (Box 49)
    - EBRD: Budapest Meeting, 1992 (Box 49)
    - EBRD: Conference, 1992 (Box 49)
    - EBRD: Journal, 1992 (Box 49)
    - EBRD: October 1993 Meeting (Box 49)
    - EBRD: Paper, 1995-1999 (Box 49)
      Files for report on "Entry, Productivity, and Investment" for EBRD
    - EBRD: Privatization Project, 1992 (Box 49)
    - EBRD: Reports, 1991-1992 (Box 49)
    - ECAAR (Economists Against the Arms Race): Missile Defense, 2000-2004 (Box 21)
      Files related to Economists Allied for Arms Reduction and missile defense
    - ECAAR: South Africa, 1995 (Box 21)
    - Ecology and Economics Student Conference, 1988 (Box 21)
    - Econometric Institute, 1993 (Box 48)
      Files related to Econometric Institute at University of Rotterdam
    - Econometric Society, 2015 (Box 21)
    - Econometric Society, 1980-1993; 2 folders (Box 48)
      Files related to serving on Nominating Committee, on the Council, and as a Fellow of the Econometric Society
    - Econometric Society Barcelona Meeting, 1990 (Box 21)
    - Econometric Society Korea Meeting, 1991 (Box 21)
      Presentation on "Use of Information in Decision Analysis"
    - Econometric Society Nominations, 1987-2011 (Box 21)
    - Econometric Society: Council, 1977-1978 (Box 49)
    - Econometric Society: Fellowship Elections, 1987-1993 (Box 49)
    - Econometric Society: Seoul, 1991 (Box 49)
      Files related to Econometric Society conference
    - Economic Conflict Program, 1976 (Box 21)
      Files for report given to Office of Naval Research
    - Economic Conversion Center, 1993 (Box 49)
    - Economic Security Seminar, 1991 (Box 49)
    - Economic Theory and Complexity, 1995 (Box 21)
      Presentation given at Santa Fe Institute conference
    - Economic Transition Group, 1994-2001 (Box 49)
      Files related to meetings and conference on USSR transition to a market economy
    - Economics and Philosophy, 1987-2008 (Box 49)
    - Economics of National Security, 1986-1988 (Box 21)
    - Edge Lecture, undated (Box 21)
    - Edwards Visit, 2014 (Box 21)
      Files and presentation on health spending for Edwards Lifesciences
    - EEE (Endowment For Excellence in Education), 1993 (Box 49)
      Files related to serving on board
    - Einstein Archives, 1988 (Box 49)
    - Elster Central Bank Conference, 1992 (Box 21)
      Invitation to conference on central banks in transitioning Eastern Europe
    - Elster Colloquium, 1985-1986 (Box 21)
      Files and paper presented at Colloquium on Rationality and Social Norms
    - Emeritus Talk, 2006 (Box 21)
      Talk on "Intrasensitivity of Majority Voting" given to Emeritus Council at Stanford
    - Encyclopedia of Economics, 1981-1982 (Box 49)
      Files related to serving on advisory council
    - Environmental and Energy Policy Analysis Center, 2010 (Box 21)